Yingxue Zhang

Binghamton University Address: 129 Passaic Ave, APT 301, Kearny, NJ 07032

Computer Science Department Email: yzhang42@binghamton.edu
Engineering Building, N04 Homepage: https://yingxuezhang.com
4400 Vestal Pkwy E Github: https://github.com/yingxue-zhang

Binghamton, NY 13902 Phone: +1 (551) 263-9462

Research Summary

Broad research interests include: (1) designing novel data mining, machine learning and AI techniques to solve spatial-temporal big data analytics problems related to smart cities, public safety, sustainability and business, and (2) human behavior analysis and decision making with meta-learning, reinforcement learning and imitation learning.

Work Experience

Binghamton University, Binghamton, NY

Assistant Professor Aug 2022-Present

Worcester Polytechnic Institute, Worcester, MA

Research Assistant Aug 2018-Aug 2020

Nuro, Mountain View, CA

Research Intern May 2021-Aug 2021

Education

Worcester Polytechnic Institute (WPI), Worcester, MA Aug 2018-May 2022

Ph.D., Data Science, Data Science Department

Thesis: Spatial-Temporal Generative Adversarial Learning.

Stevens Institute of Technology, Hoboken, NJ Aug 2016-May 2018

M.S., Financial Engineering (Data Science Track), School of Business

Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, China

Sep 2012-July 2016

B.E., Computer Science, School of Electronic, Information and Electrical Engineering

Teaching Experience

Computer Science Department, Binghamton University

Instructor Aug 2022-Present

Course: Python and Data Mining (INFO 501)

Computer Science Department, Worcester Polytechnic Institute

Teaching Assistant Jan 2020-Present

Course: Database Management Systems (CS 542)

Foisie Business School, Worcester Polytechnic Institute

Guest Lecturer May 2021

Course: Introduction to Data Science (DS1010)

Data Science Department, Worcester Polytechnic Institute

Teaching Assistant Aug 2020-Dec 2020

Course: Reinforcement Learning (DS 595)

Conference Publications

- [C1] Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Xun Zhou, Zhenming Liu and Jun Luo. C^3 -GAN: Complex-Condition-Controlled Urban Traffic Estimation through Generative Adversarial Networks. 2021 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM).
- [C2] Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Xun Zhou, Xiangnan Kong and Jun Luo. Curb-GAN: Conditional Urban Traffic Estimation through Spatio-Temporal Generative Adversarial Networks. In Proceedings of the 26th ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD' 20).
- [C3] Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Xun Zhou and Jun Luo. cST-ML: Continuous Spatial-Temporal Meta-Learning for Traffic Dynamics Prediction. 2020 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM).
- [C4] Han Bao, Xun Zhou, Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Yiqun Xie. COVID-GAN: Estimating Human Mobility Responses to COVID-19 Pandemic through Spatio-Temporal Conditional Generative Adversarial Networks. In Proceedings of the 28th ACM SIGSPATIAL International Conference on Advances in Geographic Information Systems.
- [C5] Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Xun Zhou, Xiangnan Kong and Jun Luo. Traffic-GAN: Off-Deployment Traffic Estimation with Traffic Generative Adversarial Networks. 2019 IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM).
- [C6] Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Xun Zhou and Jun Luo. STrans-GAN: Spatially-Transferable Generative Adversarial Networks for Urban Traffic Estimation. *Under submission*.

Journal Publications

- [J1] Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Xun Zhou, Jun Luo and Zhi-Li Zhang. Urban Traffic Dynamics Prediction A Continuous Spatial-Temporal Meta-Learning Approach. In ACM Transactions on Intelligent Systems and Technology (TIST).
- [J2] Han Bao, Xun Zhou, Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, and Yiqun Xie. COVID-GAN+: Estimating Human Mobility Responses to COVID-19 through Spatio-Temporal Generative Adversarial Networks with Enhanced Features. In ACM Transactions on Intelligent Systems and Technology (TIST).
- [J3] Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Xun Zhou, Xiangnan Kong and Jun Luo. Off-Deployment Traffic Estimation A Traffic Generative Adversarial Networks Approach. In IEEE Transactions on Big Data (TBD).
- [J4] Yingxue Zhang, Yanhua Li, Xun Zhou, Zhenming Liu and Jun Luo. C^3 -GAN⁺: Complex-Condition-Controlled Generative Adversarial Networks with Enhanced Embeddings. *Under submission*.

Conference IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM)

Presentations Conference Presentor

Virtual event, Nov 2020

ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining
Conference Presentor

Virtual event, Aug 2020

Graduate Research Innovation Exchange (GRIE)

Poster Presentor Virtual event, Feb 2020

IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM)

Conference Presentor Beijing, China, Nov 2019

Graduate Research Innovation Exchange (GRIE)

Worcester, MA, Feb 2019

Poster Presentor

Mentoring Mentor for Yiqing Zhang, Ph.D. student in Data Science, WPI Spring 2021

Experience Project: Activity-Based Travel Demand Modelling for Urban Planning

Mentor for Zixuan Zhang, Graduate student in Data Science, WPI Fall 2020

Project: Spatial-Temporal Data Analytics For Travel Demand Prediction

Awards and ICDM 2020 Student Travel Award 2020

Fellowships ACM SIGKDD Student Registration Award 2020

Scholarship for International Students, Stevens Institute Technology 2016-2017

Academic Reviewer for AAAI (2020, 2021), WWW (2020,2021) IJCAI (2019, 2020, 2021), Service KDD (2019, 2020, 2021), SDM (2020, 2021), ICLR 2021, CIKM (2019, 2020, 2021),

ICDM (2020, 2021), SDM (2020, 2021), ICER 2021, CIRM

Technical Python, R, C/C++

Skills PyTorch, TensorFlow, LATEX, Matlab, SQL

References Zhi-Li Zhang

Qwest Chair Professor and McKnight Distinguished University Professor

Associate Director for Research, Digital Technology Center

Department of Computer Science and Engineering

University of Minnesota

4-192 Keller Hall, 200 Union Street SE,

Minneapolis, MN 55416 Email: zhzhang@cs.umn.edu Phone: (612) 625-8568

Yanhua Li

Associate Professor

Computer Science Department Worcester Polytechnic Institute Atwater Kent 130, 100 Institute Rd,

Worcester, MA 01609 Email: yli15@wpi.edu

Xun Zhou

Associate Professor

Department of Business Analytics, Tippie College of Business

The University of Iowa

S280 PBB 21 East Market Street,

Iowa City, IA 52242-1994 Email: xun-zhou@uiowa.edu Phone: (319) 384-3335